<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CfgMgmtCamp</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/</link><description>Recent content on CfgMgmtCamp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kangaroot</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/kangaroot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/kangaroot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Alexander Olofsson</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/alexanderolofsson/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/alexanderolofsson/</guid><description>Alexander Olofsson is a programmer and sysadmin employed at Linköping University, working to automate and modernize infrastructure as well as tooling to allow for quicker development and faster deliveries.</description></item><item><title>Damien Duportal</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/damienduportal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/damienduportal/</guid><description>Træfik&amp;rsquo;s Developer Advocate at Containous and freelancer.
Former Training Engineer at CloudBees.
Docker mentor.
Human stack focused.
Rock climber.
Passionated.
Talk to me!</description></item><item><title>You Had One Job: Configuring the Edge Router</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/traefik/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/traefik/</guid><description>In the era of containers and other dynamic platforms, management of entry points is becoming a great challenge, with the large amounts of application deployments requiring entry points to update often.
And the patterns for routing, blue / green or canary, are challenging to scale.
You want secured HTTPS requests on your applications, while ensuring certificates are up to date on these ephemeral URLs, thus requiring a lot of plumbing.</description></item><item><title>Schedule Online</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/newschedule19/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/newschedule19/</guid><description>The schedule is online, while we&amp;rsquo;re still working out the last details, please have a look at schedule.
The schedule overview give you a birds eye view on all te talks, you can click on the talk for more information and continue to the talk page. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a list of the speakers, take a look at speaker and you&amp;rsquo;ll get an overview per speakers. We&amp;rsquo;ll be adding more information about the rooms and halls soon, but you already have a draft schedule.</description></item><item><title>Container Security Workshop</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/sysdig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/sysdig/</guid><description>In this 3-hour use-case driven training session we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the most important container security techniques : (best practices, platform features, image scanning, run-time security and forensics) with Docker, Kubernetes and other 3rd party open source tools (Anchore, Falco and Sysdig Inspect).
Agenda: Container security best practices (~30m) : Learn what are the security best practices building your containers: privileges, resource limits, Dockerfile options, rebuild process, etc. Kubernetes platform security features (~45min) : Host security configuration, Kubernetes RBAC, Kubernetes Security Policy, Kubernetes Network Policy and other Admission Controllers, etc.</description></item><item><title>CityTV.nl</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/citytvnl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/citytvnl/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sigi-I/O</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/sigio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/sigio/</guid><description/></item><item><title>StickerMule</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/stickermule/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/stickermule/</guid><description/></item><item><title>OlinData</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/olindata/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/olindata/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Francois Bayart</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/francoisbayart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/francoisbayart/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ansible in a dev, acc and prod environment. A real life example</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/ansibledevaccprod/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/ansibledevaccprod/</guid><description>Ansible is often used in a develop, accept and production environment, but there are no general use cases available.
This presentation shows how we solved the dev, acc and prod environment issues within a clients setup and how this can aid you in solving similar problems.</description></item><item><title>Battle of the circuit breakers: Istio vs Hystrix</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/battlebreaker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/battlebreaker/</guid><description>Kubernetes in general, and Istio in particular, have changed a lot the way we look at Ops-related constraints: monitoring, load-balancing, health checks, etc. Before those products became available, there were already available solutions to handle those constraints.
Among them is Hystrix, a Java library provided by Netflix.
From the site: &amp;ldquo;Hystrix is a latency and fault tolerance library designed to isolate points of access to remote systems, services and 3rd party libraries, stop cascading failure and enable resilience in complex distributed systems where failure is inevitable.</description></item><item><title>CNAB: packaging for distributed applications with multiple toolchains</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/cnab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/cnab/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re managing distrubyted applications you&amp;rsquo;re probably using a variety of tools that serve specific purposes.
Terraform, Helm, Compose, CloudFormation, Pulumi, ARM templates, etc. No one tool solves all your needs.
And new tools come along regularly. But all tools tend to invent there own packaging.
In this talk we&amp;rsquo;ll introduce the Cloud Native Application Bundles (CNAB) specification, and some associated tooling.
CNAB embraces the multi-tool world and allows for packaging up multiple formats and their accompanying toolchains into a single artefact.</description></item><item><title>Observabilty at scale</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/observescale/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/observescale/</guid><description>This is a talk about how Criteo (http://labs.criteo.com/) is monitoring 30k servers across 8 datacenters.
I&amp;rsquo;ll also talk about observability and what it means and how you should focus on observability rather than monitoring Technologies would include prometheus, bigGraphite, cassandra and elasticsearch.</description></item><item><title>Three years of automating large scale networks using Salt</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/saltscaling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/saltscaling/</guid><description>Cloudflare started its automation efforts using Salt about three years ago.
We have since open sourced many components, fixes and features in collaboration with other networks.
Salt is now one of the most widely-adopted open-source automating frameworks within the network community.
Already well known to the system community, Salt has reached its maturity on the network automation side as well.
Today, Salt natively provides integrations with well-known open-source libraries and tools, including: NAPALM, NetBox, Netmiko, Junos PyEZ (junos-eznc), Arista pyeapi, CiscoConfParse, as well as features for PeeringDB, and many others.</description></item><item><title>Keynote Announcement</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/keynote2019announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/keynote2019announcement/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce our keynote speakers, Charity Majors and Steve Traugott.
Charity Majors will be talking about Infrastructure Observability and Steve Traugott will be talking about the past and future of Infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Second AulaB</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/room/1.baula/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/room/1.baula/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nicolas Frankel</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/nicolasfrankel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/nicolasfrankel/</guid><description>Developer Advocate with 15+ years experience consulting for many different customers, in a wide range of contexts (such as telecoms, banking, insurances, large retail and public sector).
Usually working on Java/Java EE and Spring technologies, but with narrower interests like Software Quality, Build Processes and Rich Internet Applications.
Currently working for Exoscale.
Also double as a teacher in universities and higher education schools, a trainer and triples as a book author.</description></item><item><title>Emanuil Tolev</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/emanuiltolev/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/emanuiltolev/</guid><description>Emanuil is a Community Engineer with Elastic, the company behind the open source Elastic Stack (Elasticsearch, APM, Kibana, Beats, and Logstash). He&amp;rsquo;s based in London. He used to be a freelance web developer + ops lead and ran a small open science web dev consultancy with partners for several years. Interested in mentorship, inclusion, small businesses, archery and always curious about how the world works in detail.</description></item><item><title>Main AulaD</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/room/0.daula/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/room/0.daula/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Philipp Krenn</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/philippkrenn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/philippkrenn/</guid><description>Philipp lives to demo interesting technology.
Having worked as a web, infrastructure, and database engineer for more than ten years, Philipp is now working as a developer advocate at Elastic - the company behind the open source Elastic Stack consisting of Elasticsearch, Kibana, Beats, and Logstash.
Based in Vienna, Austria, he is constantly traveling Europe and beyond to speak and discuss about open source software, search, databases, infrastructure, and security.</description></item><item><title>Aditi Puntambekar</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/aditipuntambekar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/aditipuntambekar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Alexander Brianceau</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/alexanderbrianceau/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/alexanderbrianceau/</guid><description>After studying Cybersecurity, Alexandre worked for several years at several French integrators and IT services companies to ensure production security missions as a solution integrator as well as a consultant.
For more than a year, he has been working for the RUDDER open-source continuous configuration solution as Customer Success Manager.
It supports the success of users and ensures the follow-up of customers, making it possible to capitalize on a large number of feedback experiences.</description></item><item><title>Alexis Mousset</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/alexismousset/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/alexismousset/</guid><description>Alexis Mousset is a system engineer, and a Rudder developer since 2015.
He works specifically on the Rudder&amp;rsquo;s configuration policies and packaging, and he (almost) enjoys documenting things.</description></item><item><title>Andrew Martin</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/andrewmartin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/andrewmartin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ansible Community Update</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/ansicommi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/ansicommi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Austin Macdonald</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/austinmacdonald/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/austinmacdonald/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ben Ford</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/benford/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/benford/</guid><description>Developer Advocate on the Puppet Community Team.</description></item><item><title>Benoît Peccatte</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/benoitpeccatte/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/benoitpeccatte/</guid><description>Benoit Peccatte started out as a developer for air traffic control systems but quickly became more interested in writing code generators to automate his job.
After meeting some smart sysadmins on the beach, he switched jobs and has been automating servers for the past decade.
He stumbled across open source in engineering school, and quickly became convinced that free software is the only way to keep software maintainable whatever happens in the future.</description></item><item><title>Bernhard Hopfenmüller</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/bernhardhopfenmuller/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/bernhardhopfenmuller/</guid><description>Bernhard works for ATIX AG as a part-time developer, consultant and trainer in the devops field.
Among other things he works with Ansible, Python, Kafka and Foreman to build beautiful things</description></item><item><title>Bernhard Suttner</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/bernhardsuttner/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/bernhardsuttner/</guid><description>Bernhard Suttner is leading the software development team of ATIX AG - a company near Munich, Germany.
He is working on the Foreman / Katello based product orcharhino. In this role he is actively involved in many open source projects.</description></item><item><title>Boris Odnopozov</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/borisodnopozov/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/borisodnopozov/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bram Vogelaar</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/bramvogelaar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/bramvogelaar/</guid><description>Bram spent the first part of his career as a Molecular Biologist, he then moved on to supporting his peers by building tools and platforms for them with a lot of Open Source technologies, after which he joined Inuits to focus on helping more people to deliver their software with Open Source tools.</description></item><item><title>Carles Garcia Cabot</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/carlesgarciacabot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/carlesgarciacabot/</guid><description>Carles Garcia Cabot is a computer engineer at CERN, the European Organization for Nuclear Research.
There, he has previously developed software for a Large Hadron Collider experiment and worked on enhancing the network architecture for the data center.
Currently he is a member of the Configuration Management team and is developing tools to configure the IT infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Charity Majors</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/charitymajors/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/charitymajors/</guid><description>Charity is a co-founder and engineer at Honeycomb.io, a startup that blends the speed of time series with the raw power of rich events to give you interactive, iterative debugging of complex systems. She has worked at companies like Facebook, Parse, and Linden Lab, as a systems engineer and engineering manager, but always seems to end up responsible for the databases too. She loves free speech, free software and a nice peaty single malt.</description></item><item><title>David Davis</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/daviddavis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/daviddavis/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer at Red Hat and I write code.</description></item><item><title>Dirk Goetz</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/dirkgoetz/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/dirkgoetz/</guid><description>Dirk Goetz is working as Senior Consultant and Trainer for NETWAYS.
As part of his daily work he writes concepts, implements, reviews and teaches Puppet, Ansible and Foreman in many different environments.
He created a training course based on Open Source Puppet for his employer and the official Foreman Training as corporate project of NETWAYS and the Foreman Project.</description></item><item><title>Eduard Jilavu</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/eduardjilavu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/eduardjilavu/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Eric Sorenson</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/ericsorenson/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/ericsorenson/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Evgeni Golov</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/evgenigolov/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/evgenigolov/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ewoud Kohl van Wijngaarden</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/ewoudkohlvanwijngaarden/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/ewoudkohlvanwijngaarden/</guid><description>Passionate open source user.
Long time contributor to The Foreman.
Recent(ish) Red Hat employee.</description></item><item><title>Felix Frank</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/felixfrank/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/felixfrank/</guid><description>Felix has been running distributed systems since 2004 and likes using and tinkering with various automation tools.
Special interests have included Puppet, Ansible, and mgmt.
He very occasionally updates a blog, and otherwise tries to get enough exercise to wind down from his day job running Hadoop clusters for The unbelievable Machine Company.</description></item><item><title>Felix Kronlage</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/felixkronlage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/felixkronlage/</guid><description>Being an Open Source and unix geek Felix has been in the IT infrastructure service consulting business since the late 1990s.
Mostly concerned with keeping Open Source solutions up and available he enjoys to fiddle deep down and through the whole stack yet covering the wholistic aspects of technical infrastructure is what he enjoys the most.
If not travelling around for IT-related matters or being in front of terminals his usual habitat is being outside either road cycling, running or hiking.</description></item><item><title>Florian Heigl</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/florianheigl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/florianheigl/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gareth Greenaway</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/garethgreenaway/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/garethgreenaway/</guid><description>Gareth is the software developer at Saltstack, an occasional FLOSS Weekly co-host, and co-founder and former leader of the Southern California Linux Expo.
Gareth lives in Southern California with his wife, where they are owned by several pets.</description></item><item><title>Gareth Rushgrove</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/garethrushgrove/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/garethrushgrove/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gerard de Vos</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/gerarddevos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/gerarddevos/</guid><description>Gérard is a systems engineer (or devops engineer) and architect who helps businesses deliver value by applying DevOps and Lean principles, Continuous Delivery, and Cloud technologies.
He knows that IT services can be delivered faster, with lower risk and lower costs by applying modern architectures, organizational structures and ways of working made popular through the DevOps movement.</description></item><item><title>Gianluca Arbezzano</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/gianlucaarbezzano/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/gianlucaarbezzano/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gratien D&#39;haese</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/gratiendhaese/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/gratiendhaese/</guid><description>Gratien D&amp;rsquo;haese is a Belgian independent IT Consultant who is already 28 years active in the Unix world (and with Linux since its invention in 1991).
Gratien has a broad experience with Unix/Linux in general, Open Source software, Unix networking and security, big system administration tasks, clustering, consultancy, DevOps (chef, ansible) and project management.
Gratien is quite active in the Unix/Linux Open Source world and is giving talks around various topics since the days of the Belgian UNIX Users Group and other organizations promoting Unix/Linux and the Open Source movement.</description></item><item><title>Henning Henkel</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/henninghenkel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/henninghenkel/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ina Panova</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/inapanova/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/inapanova/</guid><description>I am a software engineer at Red Hat, working as a core developer and community co-lead of open source upstream project Pulp (https://pulpproject.org/) @ipanova</description></item><item><title>JJ Asghar</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/jjasghar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/jjasghar/</guid><description>JJ works at IBM on the IBM cloud as a Developer Advocate.
He&amp;rsquo;s focusing on the IBM Kubernetes Service trying to make companies and users have a successful on boarding to the Cloud Native ecosystem.
He lives and grew up in Austin, Texas.
He enjoys a good strong stout, hoppy IPA, and some team building Artemis, madding Dwarf Fortress or Rimworld or possibly pair programming cluster Factorio.
He&amp;rsquo;s a member of the Church of Emacs, though jumps into Vim on remote machines.</description></item><item><title>James &#39;purpleidea&#39; Shubin</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/jamesshubin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/jamesshubin/</guid><description>James is a DevOps/Config mgmt. hacker and physiologist from Montreal, Canada.
He often goes by @purpleidea on the internet, and writes &amp;ldquo;The Technical Blog of James&amp;rdquo;.
He works on a Next Generation Config Management project that he started called mgmt.
He studied Physiology at university and sometimes likes to talk about cardiology.</description></item><item><title>Jon Hall</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/jonhall/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/jonhall/</guid><description>Jon is a Principal Product Manager at BMC, with a lead role on enterprise support tooling.
A passionate advocate of user-experience driven product design, a significant part of his work is focused on the emergence of DevOps and software-defined infrastructure in large enterprises, and its cultural impact on established technical support channels.</description></item><item><title>Julien Pivotto</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/julienpivotto/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/julienpivotto/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Katerina Koutsonikoli</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/katerinakoutsonikoli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/katerinakoutsonikoli/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kris Buytaert &amp; Toshaan Bharvani</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/kristosh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/kristosh/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lee Briggs</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/leebriggs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/leebriggs/</guid><description>Lee Briggs is Senior Infrastructure Engineer at Apptio.
With almost 10 years experience designing, building and maintaining distributed and complex systems, he wears the scars of many monitoring systems and deployment tools.
When he&amp;rsquo;s not trying to put monolithic applications in containers, he enjoys playing and watching soccer and walks with family and dog, Toby.</description></item><item><title>Martin Alfke</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/martinalfke/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/martinalfke/</guid><description>Martin is a longtime Puppet user and trainer who supports companies in building IT automation including CI/CD pipelines.
Martin is not a developer, or as he prefers to say: &amp;ldquo;Naming me a developer is an insult to every developer in the world.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Matthias Dellweg</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/matthiasdellweg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/matthiasdellweg/</guid><description>After finishing his doctorate in theoretical physics, Matthias Dellweg started working as an open source software engineer at ATIX AG.
Since then he contributed to projects like foreman, katello, subscription-manager pulp and their environs.</description></item><item><title>Mattias Gees</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/mattiasgees/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/mattiasgees/</guid><description>Mattias is a solutions engineer at Jetstack where he helps clients setup Kubernetes clusters and migrate their workloads to it.
He has a deep understanding of Kubernetes and the applications you can run on it.</description></item><item><title>Mircea Ulinic</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/mirceaulinic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/mirceaulinic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nicolas Charles</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/nicolascharles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/nicolascharles/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pablo Suárez Hernández</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/pablosuarezhernandez/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/pablosuarezhernandez/</guid><description>Pablo holds a BEng. Computer System Engineering from University of La Laguna. Tenerife. Spain.
He is a Python Backend Software Engineer at SUSE Linux and part of the SUSE Manager &amp;amp; Salt Team where he is actively developing on SUSE Manager &amp;amp; Uyuni and its integration with Salt.
He has lots of contributions to the Salt project, such the Snapper and Kubernetes modules, core improvements and bug fixing.
Pablo is also involved in the local communities of Arduino, Raspberry-Pi, FLOSS and Linux.</description></item><item><title>Patrick Meyer</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/patrickmeyer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/patrickmeyer/</guid><description>Hey, I&amp;rsquo;m Patrick!
I&amp;rsquo;m part of the operations team and developer of infrastructure software at InnoGames.
Part of my work is to contribute to open source tools and projects.</description></item><item><title>Per Buer</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/perbuer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/perbuer/</guid><description>Former programmer, sysadmin. Worked more or less exclusively on OSS all my life.
Founded Varnish Software at some point and worked there for 7 years. Cofounded IncludeOS.</description></item><item><title>Peter Souter</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/petersouter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/petersouter/</guid><description>Peter Souter is a Technical Account Manager at HashiCorp.
He&amp;rsquo;s loved CfgMgmtCamp ever since he attended the first in 2014, and has worn various hats, whilst speaking and working with Puppet and HashiCorp tools over the years.</description></item><item><title>Pulp Users Love Plugins</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/pulpplugins/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/pulpplugins/</guid><description>Benefits fueled by the modularity of the pulp plugin ecosystem by taking the example of pulp_deb and pulp_gem.
Pulp is a rest-api driven, plugin based framework for content repository management.
Despite being used unmediated, it is also employed as a key backend component in foreman/katello.
Its complete rewrite, needing a reimplementation of all content plugins, invites for experimentation with new technologies.
In this talk we introduce the new version of one of those plugins for debian packages, with its unique challenges.</description></item><item><title>Quirin Pamp</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/quirinpamp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/quirinpamp/</guid><description>Quirin Pamp is a software engineer with ATIX AG in Munich, Germany.
In this capacity he contributes to open-source projects in and around the Foreman/Katello ecosystem.
Unrelated interests include logic and cycling.</description></item><item><title>R.I. Pienaar</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/ripienaar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/ripienaar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ramez Hanna</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/ramezhanna/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/ramezhanna/</guid><description>observability lead at criteo</description></item><item><title>Raphael Gauthier</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/raphaelgauthier/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/raphaelgauthier/</guid><description>Front-end developer &amp;amp; UX designer @Rudder.</description></item><item><title>Raphaël Pinson</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/raphaelpinson/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/raphaelpinson/</guid><description>Raphaël Pinson (aka raphink) is an infrastructure developer and trainer at Camptocamp.
He focuses on automation and the implementation of DevOps practices mainly in Puppet, Docker/Kubernetes/OpenShift/Rancher and Terraform.
He is also involved in the Voxpupuli, Augeas and Terraform communities.</description></item><item><title>Seth Vargo</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/sethvargo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/sethvargo/</guid><description>Seth Vargo is a Developer Advocate at Google.
Previously he worked at HashiCorp, Chef Software, CustomInk, and a few Pittsburgh-based startups.
He is the author of Learning Chef and is passionate about reducing inequality in technology.
When he is not writing, working on open source, teaching, or speaking at conferences, Seth enjoys spending time with his friends and advising non-profits.</description></item><item><title>Simon McCartney</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/simonmccartney/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/simonmccartney/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Steve Traugott</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/stevetraugott/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/stevetraugott/</guid><description>Steve Traugott&amp;rsquo;s 1998 USENIX paper &amp;ldquo;Bootstrapping an Infrastructure&amp;rdquo; helped kick-start our community.
He&amp;rsquo;s been coding since the 1970&amp;rsquo;s, on platforms ranging from embedded systems to supercomputers.
He helped port the Mach kernel to IBM mainframes, and UNIX System V to PC&amp;rsquo;s.
He is former Vice President of trading floor infrastructure engineering for Chase Manhattan Bank, former NASA, and a U.S. Air Force veteran.
Today, Steve and his family operate an innovation space in Livermore, California.</description></item><item><title>Stuart Preston</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/stuartpreston/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/stuartpreston/</guid><description>Stuart&amp;rsquo;s career spans a couple of decades of consultancy, advisory and CTO positions mostly in the Microsoft app dev world.
These days he works in the Product/Engineering team at Chef and helps design and build our Microsoft ecosystem story with Windows, PowerShell, Azure and Azure DevOps.
He has been a contributor to open source Chef for many years and literally wrote the book on Using Chef with Microsoft Azure.
Stuart was awarded Microsoft MVP status in 2016.</description></item><item><title>Terraform Hack Day</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/terraformhackday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/terraformhackday/</guid><description>Terraform Hack Day Please join us on February 6th for the CfgMgmtCamp Terraform Hack Day!
This will be chance to work on Terraform with folks from HashiCorp, as well as other contributors.
Core Providers Bugs and features Pull-requests Tools and plugins Room and other details TBC
Please remember to register through the general Config Management Camp registration system.</description></item><item><title>Tim Meusel</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/timmeusel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/timmeusel/</guid><description>Tim (bastelfreak]) Meusel works as a DevOps Engineer for GoDaddy EMEA in Cologne, Germany where he develops and maintains a big public cloud platform.
Tim is the driving force behind various open source solutions at work.
He founded the VirtAPI-Stack and is a very active Vox Pupuli Maintainer.
Tim has been doing work in the DevOps area since 2009 and is persuing Puppet solutions since 2012.
Recently he was reelected to serve on the Vox Pupuli Project Management Committee.</description></item><item><title>Tomer Brisker &amp; Greg Sutcliffe</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/tomerbrisker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/tomerbrisker/</guid><description>Tomer:
Foreman core maintainer and release manager.
Senior Software Engineer at Red Hat Israel.
Long time Linux geek and Open Source advocate.
Board member of the Israeli FOSS non-profit, Hamakor.
Greg:
Foreman Community Manager, data scientist, tinkerer, and FOSS evangelist. Don&amp;rsquo;t mention bad statistics in his presence unless you want a lecture :)</description></item><item><title>Ton Kersten</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/tonkersten/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/tonkersten/</guid><description>Ton Kersten is a Linux consultant and trainer at AT Computing in the Netherlands where he helps customers with all kinds of Linux challenges. He also tries to teach them the Linux and Ansible way of life.
He enjoys music, photography, playing darts (badly), good food, beer and whisky.</description></item><item><title>Ulf Månsson</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/ulfmansson/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/ulfmansson/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vladimir Vitkov</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/vladimirvitkov/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/vladimirvitkov/</guid><description>Vladimir is a sysadmin/devops/automation guy with more than 15 years of experience in almost every imaginable sphere.
He had helped create, maintain and optimize small sites, multibilion worldwide infrastructures and everything in between.
For the last 7 years vladimir is actively working with cloud services (both public and private).
He have seen the good, the bad and the ugly and strives to make them go away.</description></item><item><title>Wim Bonthuis</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/wimbonthuis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/wimbonthuis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ops hates containers! Why?</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/opscontainer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/opscontainer/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Docker, Docker, Docker, Docker, &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, developers really love Docker.
Usually one sees the no longer need for configuration management, the easy way to spin up a platform on a laptop, the low resource footprint. But how do you deploy laptops in data centers?
This talk will give you an insight how we (more Ops then Dev) started to learn (and love) containers, the issues we saw when running them in larger scale and how Ops people should start dealing with Container technologies.</description></item><item><title>Michael Hrivnak</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/michaelhrivnak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/michaelhrivnak/</guid><description>Michael Hrivnak is a Principal Software Engineer at Red Hat.
After leading development of early registry and distribution technology for container images, he became involved with solving real-world orchestration problems on Kubernetes.
He now works on the Automation Broker and Operator SDK, projects that automate application management on Kubernetes by incorporating tools such as Ansible and Helm.
Experienced in both software and systems engineering, Michael is excited to be writing software for systems engineers.</description></item><item><title>Mihaela Drumeva</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/mihaeladrumeva/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/mihaeladrumeva/</guid><description>My name is Mihaela Drumeva, Micky for short and my passion is all things automation! If I need to perform a task more than twice, I want to automate it. My 6 year career has spanned 3 companies and over 6 diverse teams, from development to test, build and infrastructure.
As well as my day job as an operations engineer my main area of interest is in enhancing and automating new and exiting processes to increase productivity, confidence and quality.</description></item><item><title>Robyn Bergeron</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/robynbergeron/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/robynbergeron/</guid><description>Community Architect for @Ansible at @RedHat at (soooooon) @IBM.
Former @Fedora Project Leader.
Connector of humans, contributor, co-conspirator.</description></item><item><title>Toshaan Bharvani</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/toshaanbharvani/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/toshaanbharvani/</guid><description>Toshaan Bharvani is a IT consultant, currently self-employed at VanTosh, with a interest in Open Source Software and IT Hardware.
He started his IT interest at a very early age, when his father gave him his first own PC components.
Ever since he has been interested in IT hardware and software.
In business, he tends to combine higher level applications with lower level systems.
Toshaan has been involved for some time now in some open source projects and communities.</description></item><item><title>&#39;Shift Left Security&#39;, what the funk does that mean?!</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/shiftleft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/shiftleft/</guid><description>In the agile, lean, devops communities people talk about improving security by &amp;ldquo;shifting left&amp;rdquo;.
Patterns and tools are emerging, or re-emerging, that make security less of a pain in the development process while also making applications more secure.
I will cover tools and processes that help teams with the day to day work like code scanners, application scanners, pull requests, deployment tooling and infrastructure-as-code.
At the organisational level some relatively small changes to, for instance, the change approval process can have a big impact.</description></item><item><title>A general update on the Choria and Marionette Collective projects</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/choriamarionette/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/choriamarionette/</guid><description>Choria is a 2 year old project that started life as an easy route to using MCollective for open source Puppet users.
It has evolved to encompass a number of technologies related to large scale systems management and have been deployed on globe spanning sites with 100s of thousands of nodes and thousands of daily active users.
This talk will give an update on the projects status, progress, and will explore some of the new technologies created in this project.</description></item><item><title>Agent-side functions in Puppet 6. Wait, that&#39;s a thing?</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/puppetagent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/puppetagent/</guid><description>For a long time now, a common refrain in the #puppet IRC and now Slack channels has been explaining how Puppet functions run during compilation on the master and not on the agent.
No, really. Not on the agent.
And that&amp;rsquo;s still true.
Because running functions on the master means that the catalog is a complete representation of the state we want on the node.
But&amp;hellip; sometimes there are things that we just can&amp;rsquo;t put in the catalog, or have to be computed on the agent.</description></item><item><title>Breakfast</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakfast00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakfast00/</guid><description>We provide free breakfast with croissants, coffee and thee.</description></item><item><title>Breakfast</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakfast10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakfast10/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Building a self healing system with SaltStack</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/saltselfheal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/saltselfheal/</guid><description>As the number of servers that we are responsible for increases, the ability to manage issues on those systems becomes more and more difficult.
Situations arise like log files filling up disks, failed login attempts that could be brute force attacks, and unwanted processes and services running.
Using the Beacon system of SaltStack, we can monitor a system for these &amp;amp; other scenarios.
Pairing this with the Reactor system, we can have SaltStack remediate those systems to the desired state.</description></item><item><title>CFToolkit - New tooling in CFEngine 3.10, 3.12, and beyond</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/cftoolkit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/cftoolkit/</guid><description>The CFEngine team has been working on various scripts and tooling to make it easier to deploy, upgrade, test, and troubleshoot CFEngine installations. In this talk, we will focus on 4 new tools; cf-net (introduced in 3.10), cf-check (introduced in 3.12.1), cf-remote, and cf-policyupgrade (under development).
Some technical details will be covered, but most of the discussion will be centered around use cases and functionality. All tools covered are free and open source, written in C and Python 3.</description></item><item><title>Centralized Logging Patterns</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/centrallog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/centrallog/</guid><description>Most organizations feel the need to centralize their logs - once you have more than a couple of servers or containers, SSH and tail will not serve you well any more.
However, the common question or struggle is how to achieve that.
This talk presents multiple approaches and patterns with their advantages and disadvantages, so you can pick the one that fits your organization best:
Parse: Take the log files of your applications and extract the relevant pieces of information.</description></item><item><title>Cross-OS security hardening</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/hardening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/hardening/</guid><description>Intro We&amp;rsquo;re working to put in place a Rudder policy that covers all OS that we support at our customers, or that will be coming around (i.e. beta of a new version).
For our managed systems, it should cover distro-/OS-specific settings and that &amp;ldquo;what makes sense everywhere, will be applied everywhere&amp;rdquo;.
For our human eyes, it should have a clear design that allows for easy understanding and maintenance.
Rudder offers many options to express little details in the policy.</description></item><item><title>Don&#39;t make me log in</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/dontlogin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/dontlogin/</guid><description>How to manage (large) groups of servers using Foreman and Katello without having to log in.
Showcases katello-agent, remote execution, openscap, pxe and image based deployments with automated building via Gitlab pipelines.
I&amp;rsquo;ve set up a lab with LXD, Cloud-Init, Foreman Ansible Modules and some more automation to make my life easier.</description></item><item><title>Dr SaltStack: or How I Stopped Worrying And Replaced All The Crons</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/drsalt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/drsalt/</guid><description>Cron, a popular tool for scheduling jobs, has been used by millions of people on millions of servers around the world for several years.
As servers become less like pets and more like cattle, jobs can no longer be tied to a specific server and a scheduling system must be flexible to allow jobs to easily be scheduled across multiple servers, quickly moved from one server to another, and easily report on the status of a scheduled job.</description></item><item><title>I Don&#39;t Know What I&#39;m Doing: A Newbie Guide for Golang for DevOps</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/gonewbie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/gonewbie/</guid><description>Golang as a language has exploded with popularity since it&amp;rsquo;s first release in 2009.
It&amp;rsquo;s now the langauage behind a number of applications core to most organisations operations, such as Docker, Terraform, Kubernetes and etcd.
However, for most people used to scripting interpreted languages like Ruby and Python, it can be a bit hard to get started with. What&amp;rsquo;s all this err != nil business, and why am I getting errors when I don&amp;rsquo;t refer to a variable?</description></item><item><title>Istio: Service Mesh Network Security</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/istioservicemesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/istioservicemesh/</guid><description>Microservice security is too hard.
We must issue and rotate TLS certificates, deploy identity providers, and embed auth logic in applications.
These all require secure development, test, and maintenance effort.
Istio (a Google, IBM, and Lyft project) offers a new way: by providing a service mesh and a unified identity for each request, it offers all these things with zero application changes.
In this talk we detail:
What a service mesh is, and why Istio could revolutionise microservices Increasing application security and availability using network RBAC and circuit breakers Why all applications should use encryption by default &amp;ldquo;Free&amp;rdquo; mutual TLS between all services and rotate certs every hour Preventing token replay attacks that plague JWT Securely delegating requests between microservices</description></item><item><title>Katello and Ansible for automated testing and releasing of packages</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/katansi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/katansi/</guid><description>Katello, a plugin to The Foreman, provides package repositories to clients, allows repository snapshots and can present these snapshots to different client groups.
This, together with an extensive Ansible integration, allows for easy automation of the whole lifecycle of a package, from build, though integration testing down to the clients in QA and Production.
In this talk we will show how you can build out such a setup, integrate with your build services, spin up your test environment with the newly created package-set and promote the packages to the next level as soon as all tests are green.</description></item><item><title>Keeping Track of Stateful Infrastructure</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/trackstateinfra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/trackstateinfra/</guid><description>An overview over InnoGames infrastructure and the tools we build.
At InnoGames we have to keep track of three collocations, ~30 racks with thousands of VMs to run games for over 200 million registered users.
We have to manage our self hosted as well as various external services and preferably do so in a way that does not wake our oncall admin at 3am.
All our infrastructure is configured via a central configuration management database.</description></item><item><title>Managing large Debian repositories with Pulp (and less than 50GiB of RAM)</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/pulpdeb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/pulpdeb/</guid><description>Pulp is a platform for software repository management.
The pulp_deb plugin adds Apt-repository support for Debian packages.
Until recently, the pulp_deb implementation did not scale well for large repositories.
Synchronizing a full Debian or Ubuntu release (typically containing around 50,000 Packages) would routinely take hours before falling victim to the OOM-killer.
This talk discusses the changes we employed to fix this lamentable state of affairs.
It concludes with lessons learned for the development of pulp_deb 3.</description></item><item><title>Packer, Terraform and Jenkins - IaC &amp; CD for small stacks</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/terrapacker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/terrapacker/</guid><description>Not everything revolves around docker containers and kubernetes, some environments pine for evolution of existing models &amp;amp; practices.
Although this talk is about VMs and baking AMIs, it&amp;rsquo;s not really a step inside a time machine to ~2010.
We&amp;rsquo;ll walk though some sane patterns for:
building AMIs in a Jenkinsfile pipeline using packer testing AMIs in a Jenkinsfile pipeline using InSpec building test stacks using terraform from inside a Jenkinsfile pipeline, validating AWS infra using InSpec mapping branches to terraform environments and tfvars files using that same pipeline to deploy to production The talk is based on the experience of building out a real-world example of AMI based small stacks in https://github.</description></item><item><title>Pulp 3: Ready for a Test Drive</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/pulp3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/pulp3/</guid><description>Pulp is a platform for managing repositories of software packages, and its plugin architecture allows management of any type of content.
Pulp&amp;rsquo;s web API enables users to synchronize, upload, and publish versioned repositories with simple but flexible workflows.
This presentation will highlight simplified installation and deployment, better performance, new features, and a growing collection of plugins including rpm, python, docker, ansible, chef, ruby, file, and more in development.
Pulp 3 is approaching maturity and is ready for you to test drive.</description></item><item><title>Puppet&#39;s Type &amp; Provider Module Extraction Saga</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/puppettype/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/puppettype/</guid><description>In Puppet 6, we removed several core types and providers into modules, and published most of those onto the Puppet Forge.
This talk covers the history and motivation behind removing them, hurdles we faced, module authorship with PDK, setting up CI pipelines, and the behind the scenes view of how the extracted modules are repackaged back into Puppet agent.</description></item><item><title>Salt xor Ansible</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/saltxansible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/saltxansible/</guid><description>Salt can be used for data-driven orchestration, remote execution for any infrastructure, configuration management for any app stack, and much more.
Ansible, together with Ansible Tower brings you comprehensive enough tool for IT automation.
In this session, Pablo Suárez Hernández, Senior Software Engineer for SUSE, will break down:
How Salt competes with Ansible How SUSE is committed to the improvements and development of Salt News for the upcoming Fluorine release and future releases</description></item><item><title>SaltStack for Developers: Extending SaltStack</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/saltextend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/saltextend/</guid><description>The Salt project is already very powerful Python-based DevOps platform that ships with almost 500 remote execution modules and just over 300 state modules, it has the means and the ability to support many different systems and environments, but that doesn’t mean that they all suit your needs perfectly.
By extending Salt with your own modules or building enhancements into existing ones, you can bring the functionality that you need to increase your productivity.</description></item><item><title>Secrets management with Puppet at CERN</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/puppetcern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/puppetcern/</guid><description>The CERN IT infrastructure consists of more than 40000 Puppet-managed virtual and physical machines located in two data centers.
Many Puppet catalogs contain configuration that depends on sensitive data which has to be centrally managed but accessible only by the relevant machines.
In order to distribute the secrets to hosts via Puppet, we developed a system that provides Puppet resources that fetch secrets at catalog application time and a CLI for managing them.</description></item><item><title>Terraboard, a web interface to visualize and query Terraform states</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/terraboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/terraboard/</guid><description>The Terraform project has grown a lot in popularity since its inception in 2015.
Many resources that were not automated as code yet can now be managed this way.
The Terraboard project aims to provide a web interface to visualize and query Terraform states.</description></item><item><title>Uyuni: An open source frontend solution for managing your software-defined infrastructure with Salt</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/uyuni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/uyuni/</guid><description>Uyuni (https://www.uyuni-project.org/), an opinionated fork of the Spacewalk project, provides open source lifecycle management for today&amp;rsquo;s datacenter.
With the help of Salt for configuration management it keeps your workloads up to date and secure.
Uyuni manages all your Linux workloads.
It bootstraps physical servers, creates VMs for virtualization and cloud, builds container images, and tracks what runs on your Kubernetes clusters. All using Salt under the hood!
It provides you a high-class frontend solution to interact with Salt, manage your states, formulas with forms, and much more using a web UI.</description></item><item><title>Vox Pupuli - The Community behind Puppet</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/voxpupuli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/voxpupuli/</guid><description>Vox Pupuli is a group of more than 120 puppet module/tooling/documentation authors, all working together to ensure a continuing development process.
In 2016 we elected our first Project Management Committee with one of its goals being to include Vox Pupuli as an official project under the Software Conservancy and to guide the community.
We do not only provide a home for every orphaned puppet module; we also offer proper tooling and automation for every interested developer.</description></item><item><title>What did you InSpec?</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/inspec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/inspec/</guid><description>InSpec is an open-source testing framework created by Chef that enables you to specify compliance, security, and other policy requirements.
However, the usage is not limited to compliance checking only as you can also use it to validate systems.
And, as InSpec is code which is very readable and easy to implement it can be used in a lot of different cases.
For a DevOps engineer it is a must have to tool which can be used together with Chef, Puppet or Ansible.</description></item><item><title>cURL is not an API client</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/curlapi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/curlapi/</guid><description>This is a tale from a customer who had a Bash script to talk to the Katello API.
As tales go, the disaster was coming in form of a Katello upgrade which broke said script and and engineer was called to fix the customers problems.
The talk will show a few common errors you can make when using bash/cURL as a pseudo API client and how Python or Ruby with a proper API definition via Swagger or Apipie can prevent these.</description></item><item><title>pulp_ansible: Ansible content storage</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/pulpansible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/pulpansible/</guid><description>In this talk, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the newest Pulp 3 plugin, pulp_ansible.
Pulp is a platform for managing software packages including RPMs, Python packages, Docker images, and more.
Users can use the pulp_ansible plugin to mirror Ansible Galaxy content locally, upload and organize Ansible content in Pulp, and serve content to Ansible clients.
We&amp;rsquo;ll also talk about how Ansible Galaxy will be using pulp_ansible as its storage engine to store and serve content.</description></item><item><title>Managing Debian / Ubuntu hosts with Katello (incl. Errata)</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/katellodeb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/katellodeb/</guid><description>In this presentation I will show you how to manage Debian/Ubuntu hosts with Katello.
Last year we at ATIX AG spent a lot of time improving support for Debian-based operating systems.
With these changes it is possible to fully manage Debian / Ubuntu hosts - including package installation from content views and managing package updates using Errata.
Note that we are currently working hard to add changes to the upstream Katello project.</description></item><item><title>Ansible - &#39;Faster-than-light&#39;</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/ansiblefast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/ansiblefast/</guid><description>In recent years, Ansible has established itself as a standard tool that is frequently used in DevOps, among other areas.
Despite all flexibility and simplicity, the speed of the tool is often criticized.
In this talk we would like to discuss possibilities that can be used to increase the execution speed of Ansible, sometimes with significant profit.
The possibilities range from setting and changing individual configuration parameters to using an external execution framework.</description></item><item><title>Ansible from metal to container</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/ansimetal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/ansimetal/</guid><description>This presentation show how you can use Ansible to setup a complete datacenter from the metal to a fully functional datacenter.
The idea is to bootstrap a datacenter from a single laptop and configure all possible components through your configuration management tools.
In my presentation I will show how to use Ansible to orchestrate as many components of a datacenter as possible, going from baremetal machines, network switches, to more commonly virtual machines, sdn, sds, and other infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Automate Kubernetes Workloads with Ansible</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/ansikube/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/ansikube/</guid><description>Have you longed for a simple yet powerful way to automate workloads on Kubernetes?
Ansible, the familiar IT automation tool, makes it easier than ever to automate your cluster.
This talk introduces two practical ways to define and provision complex applications using Ansible Automation with Kubernetes.
The Automation Broker allows users to leverage Ansible Automation to define and orchestrate applications, making them available for self-service provisioning in the Service Catalog.</description></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon05/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon05/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Clients, TheForeman, and you. Reusing your server lifecycle management for client machines</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/foremanclients/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/foremanclients/</guid><description>Clients and servers nowadays can be treated much more alike than many people might think, so in this talk I&amp;rsquo;ll be going over how to extend your server management tooling to also handle clients - though perhaps not quite as well as the servers it&amp;rsquo;s designed for.</description></item><item><title>Drilling down a software bug: lessons about observability, monitoring, automation and good practices</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/drilling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/drilling/</guid><description>So, there is case, every once in a few days the kafka cluster dies and along dies the whole application resulting in revenue loss for the company.
Starting there, I would like to describe how we approached the unknown issue, assumptions, failure, trial and error, until we found the root cause: a known bug in the respective version of the famous distributed software.
Of course, every software has bugs and hitting a major one is not such uncommon but more than that, what is actually important is the actual lessons learnt during the process:</description></item><item><title>Foreman - Lifecycle management for training labs</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/foremanlifecycle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/foremanlifecycle/</guid><description>This talk will show a uncommon case study for Foreman at NETWAYS.
Our training schedule is fully packed with public and in-house training courses and having many different topics requires us to change training environments quite often and in short time to get them to different locations.
Moving away from golden images to Foreman and Puppet has enabled our Events team to provision training environments independently from technical stuff.
The Discovery Plugin allows to use the same process for handling rental notebooks for in-house training courses and big conference.</description></item><item><title>Foreman and Kubevirt for Orchestrating a Virtualized environment over Containers</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/foremankube/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/foremankube/</guid><description>Kubernetes with Kubevirt is the uprising solution for unified management of virtual machines and containers.
Foreman is well known as a complete life cycle systems management tool for provisioning, configuring and monitoring of physical and virtual servers.
The talk will focus on the newly added support for Kubevirt in Foreman which allows provisioning and configuration of Virtual Servers on top of Kubernetes with Kubevirt.
After describing the use-cases and the supported functionality provided by the integration, I intend to show a demo that combines all of the pieces and the interaction between them.</description></item><item><title>Hierarchical Config Data with Jerakia and Ansible</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/jerakia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/jerakia/</guid><description>Jerakia is standalone tool inspired by Puppet&amp;rsquo;s Hiera which allows you to separate configuration data from configuration code.
The newest iteration of Jerakia provides you a smooth integration into Ansible via a module.
This talk will give a generic overview over Jerakia and it&amp;rsquo;s intentions as well as the integration into Ansible.</description></item><item><title>How to benefit from the new plugin ecosystem in Rudder 5.0?</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/rudderplugin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/rudderplugin/</guid><description>The latest major version of the solution has brought a major new feature to the Rudder solution: a plugin ecosystem.
The Rudder software architect will present the reasons for this new feature, how it works, and what are the different plugins available.</description></item><item><title>Mgmt Config: Advanced demos and internals for hackers</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/mgmtadvanced/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/mgmtadvanced/</guid><description>Mgmt is a real-time automation tool that is fast and safe.
We try and take a fresh look at existing automation problems.
This presentation will briefly introduce the tool and spend most of the time presenting and demoing some advanced and/or complicated features and use cases in the project.
While we&amp;rsquo;re certain the audience will have experienced these sorts of difficult problems before, we hope they will appreciate our more elegant solutions.</description></item><item><title>Obal: wrapping Ansible Playbooks into a CLI app</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/obal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/obal/</guid><description>The Foreman had various scripts written in a various languages to do packaging.
In Red Hat downstream there was an entirely separate set of tools available.
The same people also worked on Pulp packaging.
To share workflows we&amp;rsquo;re standardizing on Ansible roles and playbooks.
Because running Ansible is awkward, we wrote a wrapper in Python named obal.
This allows us to provide a clean command line interface with help texts that allow self discovery of the options.</description></item><item><title>Support at scale in a DevOps world: how Swarming and Cynefin can save you from 3rd Line hell</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/devopsupport/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/devopsupport/</guid><description>As DevOps practices and modern software defined infrastructure become increasingly established in enterprises, and as the scale of delivery grows, practitioners increasingly find themselves drawn into traditional IT support structures.
Here, they find themselves expected to act as part of a classic multi-tier support structure, with at least part of their time spent acting as a 3rd line support function.
This presentation explores the problems this creates: its siloed nature creates inefficient work-in-progress queues, and reduces cross-functional collaboration and knowledge sharing.</description></item><item><title>The Foreman Community Update</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/foremanrel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/foremanrel/</guid><description>The first half of the talk with be the yearly Community Update given by Greg, summarizing the work done in the past year, notable highlights, and potential issues.
The second part will be a look to the year ahead with Tomer, as well as a more detailed look at the changes so far in the release process, and what that means for our builds in terms of frequency and stability.</description></item><item><title>Tool migration - from Puppet to mgmt and back</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/fromback/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/fromback/</guid><description>Switching out the back bone of your automation tool chain is usually painful.
It likely involves rewriting all your infrastructure code, and will either require a scary over-night cut-off, or a period in which two tools run concurrently, with operators carefully shifting functionality one step at a time.
With mgmt&amp;rsquo;s support for Puppet code, migrating becomes a lot more natural.
This session does a deep dive and shows how mgmt will allow you to use and maintain a mixed code base of both Puppet&amp;rsquo;s and mgmt&amp;rsquo;s DSLs.</description></item><item><title>UX challenges of a UI-centric config management tool</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/uxuicfgtool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/uxuicfgtool/</guid><description>One of Rudder&amp;rsquo;s main focuses is its comprehensive graphical user interface, which allows users to view and manage its configurations without writing a line of code.
The user experience and interface considerations for a tool as technical and complex, and with such potential to break things as a configuration management tool are certainly a challenge, and in some ways in unchartered territory. Rudder&amp;rsquo;s frontend developer will present an analysis of the situation, the issues encountered and the approach adopted for the improvement of UX and UI planned for 2019.</description></item><item><title>Using acceptance tests for better Puppet modules</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/puppetaccept/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/puppetaccept/</guid><description>Using rspec-puppet to write module tests is also very common.
Most of us also use rspec-puppet-facts to test with the correct OS facts.
These are all good tools and every Puppet module author should know them.
Writing acceptance tests is a lot less known.
With beaker and its plugins we can write acceptance tests with powerful assertions using serverspec on actual throw away machines.
This is the easiest way to guarantee your PRs don&amp;rsquo;t introduce regressions.</description></item><item><title>What happened in Rudder in 2018 and what&#39;s next?</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/ruddernext/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/ruddernext/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at Rudder&amp;rsquo;s new features from 2018, both in terms of the features of versions 4.3 and 5.0 as well as the new documentation and our platform for building and distributing binaries.
We will then present the provisional roadmap for 2019: let&amp;rsquo;s go to Rudder 5.1 and 5.2!</description></item><item><title>What is Rudder and when should I use it?</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/rudderwhatwhere/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/rudderwhatwhere/</guid><description>Rudder is an open source configuration management tool that includes continuous auditing (with or without remediation), compliance info and graphs and the possibility to configure everything in the UI and/or APIs.
It has been around for more than six years and has users large (think 10 000 nodes) and small around the world.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to look at the vision that lead us here, how Rudder is different from similar tools, and what users find invaluable, nice (or annoying - I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest!</description></item><item><title>What uses for observing operations of Configuration Management?</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/obserecfgmgmt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/obserecfgmgmt/</guid><description>More and more services expose their state, internal details and metrics to be observable, and improve overall quality of service.
But what about observing the infrastructure they are deployed, configured and maintained on?
What can we learn from that, and what do we need from configuration management to get these features and metrics?
Logs from installation is a good start, but they need centralization, aggregation and especially knowledge derivation from these - but also we need to observe these features over time, to trace changes, and correlate them with monitoring.</description></item><item><title>Atix</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/atix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/atix/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Benefits of taking the less traveled road</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/roadtravel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/roadtravel/</guid><description>After almost a year of running Openshift Origin in production we decided to migrate to a vanilla Kubernetes setup and during this phase we had to take some hard decisions:
we focused our approach on control: we switched from using the tools provided by the community, like ansible or kops, to writing puppet manifests; we challenged the necessity of some features: this allowed us to simplify the setup, reuse tooling/systems from bare-metal infra and have directly addressable pods; - we focused on monitoring and observability: we wrote custom probes (unit and integration tests) verifying first the user experience monitored with SLOs.</description></item><item><title>Chef and the Microsoft Ecosystem, Engineering Update</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/mschef/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/mschef/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s 2019 and at Chef we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy building new tools and integrations, as well as improving our existing open source software with the help of the community.
This session will get you up to speed on the advances and decisions that have been made over the last year in the Microsoft, Windows and Azure ecosystem and give an opportunity to ask questions of our Product/Engineering team.</description></item><item><title>Ensuring security with Foreman - OpenSCAP plugin</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/foremanscap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/foremanscap/</guid><description>Systems left with unpatched vulnerabilities can have a number of consequences.
Security compliance is a state where computer systems are scrutinized against certain defined security policy.
OpenSCAP is one such security compliance ecosystem that provides multiple tools to assist administrators and auditors with assessment, measurement, and enforcement of security baselines.
Foreman provides OpenSCAP as a plugin that enables Foreman to receive automated vulnerability assessment and security compliance audits from Foreman hosts.</description></item><item><title>Example42</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/example42/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/example42/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Inside the Secret Sauce Laboratory: Rethinking SSL in Puppet</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/sslsauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/sslsauce/</guid><description>Puppet 6 made a number of changes to the PKI / certificate layer that fix longstanding problems and add awesome new features.
This will be a technical deep dive into those changes including:
new intermediate and signing CA support improved policy autosigning for cloud auto-scaling better revocation and infrastructure crl new command line tools how to upgrade cleanly and roll new certs without breaking the world Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s had to troubleshoot Puppet SSL problems will benefit from learning about these improvements.</description></item><item><title>Mgmt Config: The Road to 0.1</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/mgmtroad/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/mgmtroad/</guid><description>Real-time, autonomous, automation.
Mgmt is a real-time automation tool that is fast and safe.
As we get closer to a 0.1 release that we&amp;rsquo;ll recommend as &amp;ldquo;production ready&amp;rdquo;, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the last remaining features that we&amp;rsquo;re aiming to land by then.
We&amp;rsquo;ll explain and demo the import and module system, classes, and native functions.
It uses a real-time, reactive programming language to model the desired state over time, and a powerful event-driven engine to apply this state.</description></item><item><title>One to rule them all? What&#39;s happening in the landscape of CMDBs</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/onecmdb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/onecmdb/</guid><description>Over the years the topic of CMDBs, asset management and inventoring things have crossed my path numerous times.
I want to give an overview of the current state of affairs: What exists in the CMDB landscape within the scope of open source solutions and why companies still write a lot of these solutions themselves to tackle their specific needs.
Furthermore I want to elaborate on what I think is actually needed when looking at the subject of asset management and when there is actually a need for a CMDB.</description></item><item><title>Scaling and monitoring your puppetserver for thousands of clients - including all pitfalls!</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/scalingpuppet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/scalingpuppet/</guid><description>Throwing hardware on your Puppetserver to scale it vertically works up to a certain level.
But how do you proceed once you reach the limit?
How do you distribute your agents over several Puppetservers evenly, but without hardcoded assignments?
How do you handle the massively increased load on your Foreman and PuppetDB intances, after the Puppetserver isn&amp;rsquo;t the bottleneck anymore?
And how the heck can this all be monitored?
I would like to show you a walkthrough from a small environment with a single physical server for Puppetserver/Foreman/PostgreSQL and a handful of agents that got scaled up to several thousand agents.</description></item><item><title>Tarmak, why do we need another Kubernetes provisioner?</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/tarmak/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/tarmak/</guid><description>Tarmak is an open-source toolkit for Kubernetes cluster lifecycle management.
It is focused on best-practice cluster security, management and operation.
This talk will clarify the reasoning behind creating Tarmak, the architecture and technologies used.
With Tarmak we tried to not reinvent the full wheel, that is why we have chosen to depend on a lot open-source tools (Terraform, Puppet, Vault, &amp;hellip;).
This talk will explain how all of this is tied together.</description></item><item><title>kr8: Kubernetes Configuration Management</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/kr8cfg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/kr8cfg/</guid><description>The abstraction layer for Configuration Management is moving away from the operating system to the orchestration layer, but the configuration management tools aren&amp;rsquo;t keeping up.
As the number of Kubernetes clusters you run grows, your ability to install components on them with slight and subtle differences becomes more and more manual.
kr8 is designed to take the heavy lifting out of this, by allowing you to manipulate yaml with a first class data templating language (jsonnet) without all the overhead of similar tools.</description></item><item><title>Applying SOLID principles to Infrastructure as Code</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/solid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/solid/</guid><description>S.O.L.I.D is an acronym for the first five object-oriented design(OOD) principles by Robert C. Martin, in the early 2000s.
These principles, when combined together, make it easy for a programmer to develop software that are easy to maintain and extend.
They also make it easy for developers to avoid code smells, easily re-factor code, and are also a part of the agile or adaptive software development.
This talk discusses our options how we can model puppet code while applying the SOLID principles.</description></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon00/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon01/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon03/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon04/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon06/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakafternoon17/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakprenoon00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/breakprenoon00/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon10/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon11/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon12/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon13/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon15/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon16/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon16/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakafternoon18/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Break</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakprenoon10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/breakprenoon10/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breakfast</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast0/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breakfast</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breakfast</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breakfast</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breakfast</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast4/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breakfast</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast5/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breakfast</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast6/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Breakfast</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/breakfast7/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Building a Devops organisation without YAML</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/yamlcomp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/yamlcomp/</guid><description>Inspired by Luke Kanies talk last year at CfgMgmtCamp to move from startups to enterprises and implement what we in the community have learned I have now started that journey at Volvo Cars.
I will talk about how we within the Consumer Commercial Digital Products are building a new organization from scratch to help transfer Volvo Cars from a traditional enterprise to a software company by creating a Devops culture and automate.</description></item><item><title>DevOps vs SRE - competing standards or friends?</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/devopsvssre/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/devopsvssre/</guid><description>Google has been practicing Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) since the early 2000&amp;rsquo;s, but only recently began speaking about it publicly.
Some have called SRE &amp;lsquo;DevOps 2.0&amp;rsquo;, while others view it as a competing standard.
This talk discusses the differences and similarities between DevOps and SRE.</description></item><item><title>Ignites</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/ignites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/ignites/</guid><description>Overengineering your personal website Bram Vogelaar Lets be honest, whether consisouly or not we all do it. In this talk we ll discuss how stupid crazy i a managed to go, while serving only a single static html page.
Monitoring your Jenkins pipelines using Prometheus Lander Van den Bulcke In order to optimize your continous delivery pipelines, and to make sure your delivery actually is continuous, it can be useful to collect some metrics about your pipelines.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure as code should contain code</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/iacode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/iacode/</guid><description>These days &amp;ldquo;infrastructure as code&amp;rdquo; means HCL, YAML, JSON.
I will never buy that JSON is a programming language.
Cloud Formation tries so hard mixing JSON with keywords that runtime become functions saying that it is a maintainable approach.
Helm pushes hard saying that YAML with some parameters that runtime get translated to a variable is a flexible and maintainable approach.
Infrastructure as code means that you are supposed to use a programming language because otherwise, it won&amp;rsquo;t work.</description></item><item><title>Introducing &#39;object-oriented operations&#39; for community-driven infrastructure-as-code</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/objectinfra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/objectinfra/</guid><description>Infrastructure as code is a proven pattern, and so is open source. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it make sense to bring a community driven approach to operational code itself?
This talk is about bringing those ideas together, to create effective open source communities for operational code on Kubernetes and on traditional machine or cloud environments.
Collaborating on complex infrastructure, and using open source to share the benefits of that collaboration, will enable us all to spend more time focused on the things which are truly different about our challenges and less on the problems we all share.</description></item><item><title>Istio: Control and Observability for Microservices</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/istioobserve/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/istioobserve/</guid><description>Istio is a new open platform to connect, manage, and secure micro-services jointly launched by IBM, Google, and Lyft.
This session will provide a technical overview of the Istio project and demonstrations of using Istio with microservices and Kubernetes.
Specifically :
Service mesh - what it is, why, and who is using it Making the deployment more secure (Using istio to get mutual tls authentication between services) Rolling out a new version to 1% of users (Using istio for traffic splitting) Making the deployment more robust (Using istio for circuit breaking and automatic request retries) Controlling the front door (Using Istio-ingressgateway instead of default Kubernetes Ingress)</description></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch00/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch01/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch05/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch06/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch07/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch08/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch08/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch15/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/lunch17/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch10/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch11/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch12/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch13/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch16/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch16/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/lunch18/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch0/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch4/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch5/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch6/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lunch</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/lunch7/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Social Event</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/social/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/social/</guid><description>The social event, aka beer event, is about 2 minutes walk from the event.
There is no registration for this part, however to get free drinks, you&amp;rsquo;ll require a token you will get at the event.
The social event start from 18:00 and goes as long as you want.
There will be free drinks for a limited time.</description></item><item><title>Solving large scale operational metadata problems using stream processing</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/metastreamprocess/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/metastreamprocess/</guid><description>Stream processing technologies are usually associated with social media, click streams, machine learning and big data however this talk will show it can be useful in solving difficult problems operations face when dealing with large server estates.
A very large scale stream processing pipeline have been built managing metadata for 100s of thousands of nodes using technologies from Choria.io and NATS.io, this talk will explore the design, performance and potential uses of such a platform.</description></item><item><title>The Unexpected (Infrastructure Management) Journey</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/journey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/journey/</guid><description>I started my first job as an operations engineer 18 months ago and I had all of those questions and many more.
Coming from development background the transition into a more ops role and a DevOps team has been a fascinating journey.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to share the lessons I learned along the way and encourage more people to blur the traditional lines.
What is it like to start new in infrastructure management land coming from unconventional background?</description></item><item><title>100 years of infrastructure: A future history</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/keynote1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/keynote1/</guid><description>RFC-1 was published 50 years ago. Infrastructure management emerged as a discrete field two decades later, and devops a decade after that. As we work to realize the full potential of networked computing and the decentralized organizations it enables, what will the next 50 years bring, and what can we do to hurry things along?
In this talk, we’ll touch on some of the roots of current infrastructure management tools and the motivation and computing science theory behind them.</description></item><item><title>CfgMgmtCamp is dead, ...</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/intro00/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/intro00/</guid><description>The opening introduction of #CfgMgmtCamp.
Config Management Camp is expanding it&amp;rsquo;s horizon beyong our traditional scope.</description></item><item><title>Configuration and configuration management with Unikernels</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/unikernels/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/unikernels/</guid><description>Unikernels are a new class of operating system.
The core idea is to merge the kernel, libraries, and application into a single image binary, operating in a single address space.
This has the potential to improve security, performance, and a few other factors.
For native Unikernel applications, this moves configuration to the build stage.
So how are we supposed to manage these applications?
How should they be configured and deployed?</description></item><item><title>Developing Applications with Kubernetes</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/appkube/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/appkube/</guid><description>Microservices revolutionized the way we look at app development and is now one of the most popular programming architectures.
Now, Docker alongside Kubernetes is changing the way teams look at deployments of these microservices.
Kubernetes provides powerful production-grade orchestration for your &amp;ldquo;Dockerized&amp;rdquo; microservices.
In this workshop, you&amp;rsquo;ll get an overview of Kubernetes, and what it provides for application development.
You&amp;rsquo;ll then go through the process of building and deploying a microservice application on Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Everyday OpenStack with Object Oriented Operations</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/objectstack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/objectstack/</guid><description>In this extended tutorial, led by Mark Shuttleworth and James Troup, you&amp;rsquo;ll see how Canonical manages to operate tens of OpenStack clouds at reasonable scale with a small but focused team.
Operating OpenStack is widely considered to be difficult. Many early implementations have ground to a halt as people struggle with combinatorial complexity and the pace of change. Object-oriented operations enable reuse of ops code in diverse settings and configurations.</description></item><item><title>Foreman Construction Day After-Noon</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/foreman1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/foreman1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fourth Generation Automation: Uniting Models and Tasks</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/4thgenauto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/4thgenauto/</guid><description>To borrow a phrase, &amp;ldquo;In the beginning was the command line.&amp;rdquo; Then we had ISConf and CFEngine, and things were good&amp;hellip; for a while.
Puppet and Chef came along, embodying the idea that infrastructure code should behave like application code. More recently, Ansible brought the concept of idempotent resources to imperative workflows, but stops short of modelling in favor of radical simplicity.
Now we&amp;rsquo;re wondering: is it possible to get the best of both worlds?</description></item><item><title>Incident Resolution as Code</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/incidentcode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/incidentcode/</guid><description>In this talk I will go in details about how we quickly resolve incidents using Prometheus and ansible.
Come and discover how we linked the monitoring, queuing systems and orchestration to do unattended incident management.
One of the main advantages of this is that we can apply technical remediation or mitigation from business metrics, even if things happen at different levels.
All of this working anywhere Prometheus and ansible run, so not only in a kube env, but also in a traditional infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Multi-cloud and on-prem Kubernetes with Object Oriented Operations</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/objectkube/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/objectkube/</guid><description>A deep dive into K8s operations, scaling, upgrades and integration across public clouds, VMware, OpenStack and bare metal, by Mark Shuttleworth and Calvin Hartwell.
Calvin leads field engineering and delivery in EMEA for Canonical, helping companies deploy and operate OpenStack and Kubernetes efficiently at scale. Mark leads Ubuntu.
Kubernetes is central to future automation and operations at the application layer across multiple cloud environments. It is an open community that is expanding very rapidly to embrace new capabilities and integrate with new services.</description></item><item><title>Observability for emerging infra: what got you here won&#39;t get you there</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/keynote0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/monday/keynote0/</guid><description>Distributed systems, microservices, containers and schedulers, polyglot persistence &amp;hellip;
modern infrastructure is ever more fluid and dynamic, chaotic and transient.
Likewise, individual engineering roles can no longer be broken down neatly into
software engineers (who write the code) and ops engineers (who deploy the code (and buffer the consequences)).
Many teams have already sailed past an event horizon of complexity and found that their old tools and processes no longer work for them.</description></item><item><title>Rudder on Docker hackathon</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/rudder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/rudder/</guid><description>Know about Docker, Rudder, or even better both?
Let&amp;rsquo;s get our heads down together and work on making it easy to just &amp;ldquo;docker run&amp;rdquo; a Rudder server.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to YAMLcamp</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/intro10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/tuesday/intro10/</guid><description>The opening introduction of the second day of CfgMgmtCamp or YAMLcamp.
Long live all YAML engineers</description></item><item><title>#puppethack Day</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/puppethack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/puppethack/</guid><description>Please join us on 6th Feb after Config Management Camp for a free #puppethack day.
#puppethack is a collaborative, relaxed community hack day. It&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity for Puppet community and staff to collaborate on fun and interesting Puppet-related projects. Fixing on modules, core Puppet code, testing, and related projects.
Please remember to register through the general Config Management Camp registration system.
Don&amp;rsquo;t forget that #puppethack, like all Puppet Community participation, falls under our community guidelines, which also contain helpful tips for using IRC, our bug tracker, and other relevant tools.</description></item><item><title>AT Computing</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/atcomputing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/atcomputing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>CFP Closed</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/cfp-over/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/cfp-over/</guid><description>Thank you all for submitting to our CFP. (Even the late folks). We are now reviewing all of your submissions (over 150). We hope to start sending out the acceptance mails soon.</description></item><item><title>Icinga</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/icinga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/icinga/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nucleus</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/nucleus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/nucleus/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Puppet</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/puppet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/puppet/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Scale Factory</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/scalefactory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/scalefactory/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Foreman Construction Day</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/foremanconstructionday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/foremanconstructionday/</guid><description>Foreman will be holding its usual Foreman Construction Day on Wednesday 6th February 2019, right after CfgMgmtCamp. Please join us!
The aim is to build upon on the previous 2-4 days of talks and discussions, and put it to use! We&amp;rsquo;re open to all members of our community, such as
New users looking for help getting started with Foreman Users looking to start contributing Code contributors to any of the core projects UX design / improvement Plugin authors (new or existing plugins) Translators / documentors This is a great opportunity to get (more) involved in the community, and spend some face-to-face hack time with other Foreman devs.</description></item><item><title>MgmtConfig Hackathon</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/mgmtconfighackathon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/mgmtconfighackathon/</guid><description>Mgmt is a real-time automation tool that is fast and safe. The main author will be on site to chat with you about mgmt, review your code, help you get your patch merged and listen to your design ideas for the project!
Come to get help implementing your first mgmt resource, write a new language function, or even get help writing your very first module! We&amp;rsquo;ll also discuss and explain any internals that anyone is curious about.</description></item><item><title>Pulp Plugin Day</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/pulppluginday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/pulppluginday/</guid><description>Pulp is a platform for managing repositories of software packages and can store any kind of binary data (e.g. cat photos). The core provides a REST API and manages files, but the real value for users is delivered by the plugins which enable core to manage a content type like a cat photo.
You are invited to join some of the Pulp developers on February 6th for Pulp Plugin Day. This will be an opportunity to learn how to use Pulp 3, add new features to an existing plugin, or start on a new plugin to support another content type.</description></item><item><title>Don&#39;t forget our Call for Proposals</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/cfp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/cfp/</guid><description>In case you aren&amp;rsquo;t following us on Twitter and and haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed. Our CFP has been open for a while now
We’re pleased to announce CfgMgmtCamp 2019, the sixth year and 8th edition. CfgMgmtCamp has evolved beyond pure configuration management, so we are evolving the topics and content of the conference. CfgMgmtCamp wants to bring all infrastructure management tools and principles together to share and learn.
While there is still almost a month left to submit your talks don&amp;rsquo;t wait to long ;)</description></item><item><title>Sponsors needed for Configuration Management Camp</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/cfs2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/cfs2019/</guid><description>Configuration Management Camp 2019 Ghent is looking for sponsors.
The sponsor documentation for Ghent 2019 is available HERE
Help us maintain Configuration Management Camp as the premier place for practitioners to build the future.</description></item><item><title>Config Management Camp 2019</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/ghent2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/ghent2019/</guid><description>Configuration Management Camp will be held in Ghent, Belgium February 4-6, 2019.
Configuration Management Camp is the event for technologists interested in adopting, improving, and using Open Source Software and frameworks for managing configuration, infrastructure, containers, clouds, virtualization, serverless, security, and more.
Our community welcomes all people interested in discussing and improving the software and practices used in building, deploying, and managing applications. Meet, exchange ideas, and learn from one another over the course of three days.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/about/</guid><description>Configuration Management Camp is the event for technologists interested Open Source Infrastructure automation and related topics This includes but is not limited to top Open Source Configuration Management , Provisioning, Orchestration, Choreography, Container Operations and many more topics.
We’re pleased to announce CfgMgmtCamp 2019, the sixt year and 8th edition. While CfgMgmtCamp has evolved beyond pure configuration management, we are evolving the topics and content of the conference. CfgMgmtCamp wants to join all infrastructure management tools and principles to come together to share and learn about infra mgmt.</description></item><item><title>HoGent</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/hogent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/hogent/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Inuits</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/inuits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/inuits/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rudder</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/rudder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/rudder/</guid><description/></item><item><title>VanTosh</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/vantosh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/vantosh/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Location</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/location/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/location/</guid><description>Configuration Management Camp takes place in a public higher eduction location.
Address HoGent - Campus SchoonMeersen
Valentin Vaerwyckweg 1
9000 Gent
+32 9 243 87 87
https://hogent.be
Getting there This is the Campus of the University College of Ghent.
The campus is conveniently located.
Train It is within walking distance of the Gent-Sint-Pieters train station
There will be signs to from the train station to the venue.
Belgian Train Service</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/codeofconduct/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/codeofconduct/</guid><description>Configuration Management Camp is a community conference intended for networking and collaboration in the community of people interested in configuration management.
We value the participation of each member of the community and want all attendees to have an enjoyable and fulfilling experience.
Accordingly, all attendees are expected to show respect and courtesy to other attendees throughout the conference and at all conference events, whether officially sponsored or not.
Exhibitors, speakers, sponsors, staff and all other attendees at Configuration Management Camp are subject to this Code of Conduct.</description></item><item><title>ExoScale</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/exoscale/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/exoscale/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mark Shuttleworth</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/markshuttleworth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/markshuttleworth/</guid><description>Mark Shuttleworth is global leader in open source and venture philanthropy. He is CEO of Canonical, which delivers open source infrastructure, applications and related services to the global technology market. He is founder of Ubuntu and benefactor of the Shuttleworth Foundation which underwrites pioneering work at the intersection of technology and society. Previously, he founded Thawte, a global leader in cryptographic security and identity, and participated in ISS mission TM-34. He studied finance and information systems at the University of Cape Town, and orbital ballistics in Zvyozdny Gorodok.</description></item><item><title>#puppethack</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/puppet0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/puppet0/</guid><description/></item><item><title>#puppethack</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/puppet1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/puppet1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Foreman Construction Day Pre-Noon</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/foreman0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/foreman0/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jerakia Day</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/jerakiahackday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/jerakiahackday/</guid><description>Jerakia Day Please join us on February 6th for the first ever Jerakia Day!
This will be your chance to meet other Jerakia devs and users, learn more about who they are and what they do, and hopefully do some work together on the project!
To get a feeling for what we could be up to, please browse through the projects in the new Jerkia github organization and see if you find any interesting bits.</description></item><item><title>Jorie Tappa</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/jorietappa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/jorietappa/</guid><description>Software Engineer at Puppet.</description></item><item><title>MgmtCamp After-Noon Hackathon</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/mgmtcamp1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/mgmtcamp1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>MgmtCamp Pre-Noon Hackathon</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/mgmtcamp0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/mgmtcamp0/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ole Herman Elgesem</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/olehermanelgesem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/speaker/olehermanelgesem/</guid><description>C and Python developer for CFEngine / Northern.tech. Passionate about programming, code quality, and security.</description></item><item><title>Pulp Plugin</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/pulp0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/pulp0/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pulp Plugin</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/pulp1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/pulp1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Terraform Hackathon</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/terraform1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/terraform1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Terraform Hackaton</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/terraform0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/wednesday/terraform0/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>