<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CfgMgmtCamp</title>
    <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CfgMgmtCamp</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Config Management Camp 2019</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/ghent2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/posts/ghent2019/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Management Camp will be held in Ghent, Belgium February 4-6, 2019.
Configuration Management Camp is the event for technologists interested in adopting, improving, and using Open Source Software and frameworks for managing configuration, infrastructure, containers, clouds, virtualization, serverless, securityy, and more.
Our community welcomes all people interested in discussing and improving the software and practices used in building, deploying, and managing applications. Meet, exchange ideas, and learn from one another over the course of three days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/about/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Management Camp is the event for technologists interested Open Source Infrastructure automation and related topics This includes but is not limited to top Open Source Configuration Management , Provisioning, Orchestration, Choreography, Container Operations and many more topics.
We’re pleased to announce CfgMgmtCamp 2019, the sixt year and 8th edition. While CfgMgmtCamp has evolved beyond pure configuration management, we are evolving the topics and content of the conference. CfgMgmtCamp wants to join all infrastructure management tools and principles to come together to share and learn about infra mgmt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/ansible/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HoGent</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/hogent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/hogent/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inuits</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/inuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/inuits/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VanTosh</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/vantosh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/sponsors/vantosh/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/location/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Management Camp takes place in a public higher eduction location.
Address HoGent - Campus SchoonMeersen
Valentin Vaerwyckweg 1
9000 Gent
+32 9 243 87 87
https://hogent.be
Getting there This is the Campus of the University College of Ghent.
The campus is conveniently located.
Train It is within walking distance of the Gent-Sint-Pieters train station
There will be signs to from the train station to the venue.
Belgian Train Service</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynote 0</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/keynote0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/keynote0/</guid>
      <description>The keynote that will blow your mind up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynote 1</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/keynote1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/keynote1/</guid>
      <description>The keynote that will impolede your mind up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The most awesome talk ever</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/awesometalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/schedule/awesometalk/</guid>
      <description>This is the most awesome talk about the most awesome topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/codeofconduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/codeofconduct/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Management Camp is a community conference intended for networking and collaboration in the community of people interested in configuration management.
We value the participation of each member of the community and want all attendees to have an enjoyable and fulfilling experience.
Accordingly, all attendees are expected to show respect and courtesy to other attendees throughout the conference and at all conference events, whether officially sponsored or not.
Exhibitors, speakers, sponsors, staff and all other attendees at Configuration Management Camp are subject to this Code of Conduct.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>