<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fringes on CfgMgmtCamp</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/</link><description>Recent content in Fringes on CfgMgmtCamp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#puppethack Day</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/puppethack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/puppethack/</guid><description>Please join us on 6th Feb after Config Management Camp for a free #puppethack day.
#puppethack is a collaborative, relaxed community hack day. It&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity for Puppet community and staff to collaborate on fun and interesting Puppet-related projects. Fixing on modules, core Puppet code, testing, and related projects.
Please remember to register through the general Config Management Camp registration system.
Don&amp;rsquo;t forget that #puppethack, like all Puppet Community participation, falls under our community guidelines, which also contain helpful tips for using IRC, our bug tracker, and other relevant tools.</description></item><item><title>Foreman Construction Day</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/foremanconstructionday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/foremanconstructionday/</guid><description>Foreman will be holding its usual Foreman Construction Day on Wednesday 6th February 2019, right after CfgMgmtCamp. Please join us!
The aim is to build upon on the previous 2-4 days of talks and discussions, and put it to use! We&amp;rsquo;re open to all members of our community, such as
New users looking for help getting started with Foreman Users looking to start contributing Code contributors to any of the core projects UX design / improvement Plugin authors (new or existing plugins) Translators / documentors This is a great opportunity to get (more) involved in the community, and spend some face-to-face hack time with other Foreman devs.</description></item><item><title>MgmtConfig Hackathon</title><link>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/mgmtconfighackathon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cfgmgmtcamp.eu/fringes/mgmtconfighackathon/</guid><description>Mgmt is a real-time automation tool that is fast and safe. The main author will be on site to chat with you about mgmt, review your code, help you get your patch merged and listen to your design ideas for the project!
Come to get help implementing your first mgmt resource, write a new language function, or even get help writing your very first module! We&amp;rsquo;ll also discuss and explain any internals that anyone is curious about.</description></item></channel></rss>